Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today
We're bringing you another
great lesson about sports part
of our sports series. That's
right and in this lesson
We are talking about maybe
the world's most favorite
sports right one of the most
popular sports in the world
Soccer or also known as
football in other countries. Yes.
Okay, so before we get
started with this great lesson
Let's take a look at
some of the words we'll
find in the dialogue
in vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
We're going to look at three words here.
The first word is wingman
wingman a wingman now wingman
isn't really related to soccer in any way
Okay, but it's a way of referring
to somebody as your right hand
So your helper your helper
your your number one guy.
Okay, right? So a wingman is
someone who helps you a lot
Exactly okay, our next word tied
tied they are tied they are tied now
This is an interesting word because
tie can be a noun verb and an
adjective, right? Exactly. So in this case
They are tied. It's an adjective meaning
they have the same score. Okay, and
tie is is a game that has
ended with no winner or loser.
Both of them had the same score
Exactly and so obviously the verb to tie is
to reach the same score as your other team
Exactly all right
Well, our third word can also be
used as a noun and a verb and it is foul
Fould fouled. Okay, so
to foul somebody is to do
something to them that
is not allowed in the sport
Okay, and so when you do this,
you have committed a foul exactly.
Okay, so you use it in the
same way to foul or a foul
Interesting well, we're going to
hear these three words in context now.
So why don't we listen
to our soccer dialogue?
You
Welcome back soccer fans.
My name is Rick Fields and as always
I am joined by my commentating
wingman Bob Copeland
and we are in the break
of soccer history today as
Ecuador and Brazil our tied one one
as we begin the second half of the 2022
World Cup The ref calls the players
for the kick off and here we go
Ecuador quickly passes the
ball to the midfield, but oh,
no, it's out of bounds. That
will be a throw in for Brazil
I just I knew has the
ball and makes a long
past of a venial and
the ref is calling off side
No question about it.
He was off side by a mile
We have a gold kick record or
Edison Mendez heads of trouble.
It's he shoots deflected
by the defender
And we have a corner kick then
Gatto takes the corner. We have a foul
Oh, no, Dada the gold keeper
has foul the Ecuadorian player
He gets a yellow card and
that will be a penalty kick
This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to
get ahead in this match
and become world champions
He gets ready for the
kick he shoots and he
Okay, so Ecuador tied with
Brazil in the 2022 World Cup.
Wow Marco I'm really happy to see that
you are able to see so far into the future
Well, I called it so in the 2022
if we do win the World Cup
You know who said it first.
All right, do you have money on that? Yes
All right, so apart from this we saw
some really great vocabulary in this lesson
So let's take a look at it
now in language takeaway
All right, we've got a lot of soccer
words for you, but they're all important
So let's take a look
at the first one kick off
Kick off kick off So a kick off.
This is how you start
a soccer game, right?
Right, so it's the very
beginning the referee blows
the whistle and you kick
the ball to another player
That's the kick off.
Okay, so our next phrase out of bounds
Out of bounds out of bounds.
Okay, out of bounds. This is a great word
So in soccer when the
ball goes out of bounds
it goes outside the
white lines, right?
Outside of the playing field. Okay,
and you can use it on all other sports
You can use it in
basketball. You can use it in
tennis or football or
anything right to any part
That is not for playing out of bounds.
What's our next word?
Throw in a throw in a throw in
Okay, so a throw in the ball
goes out of bounds Uh-huh.
How do you put
it back into play?
Obviously a throw in. Okay,
so you throw in the ball
That's the only time where a
soccer player will actually grab
the ball with his hands. All right, now
another soccer turn We have here offside
Offside offside
Okay, so this is a little
bit difficult to explain
But just imagine you're
on the soccer field.
Uh-huh. And you are
trying to score a goal
Okay, you have some
defenders, right? Right.
Those are the people who
are trying to take the ball away
And you pass the ball to somebody
who is behind the defenders.
Oh, and that person is offside
Exactly. So you must be
at all times in the same
position as the defenders
or in front of them
But you can't be all
the way in the back.
Okay, so is this a noun
or a verb or an adjective?
So this is an
adjective. He is offside.
That's his condition. Okay. Great.
Excellent explanation Marco Thank you.
All right. Now we're
going to look at three
different phrases for three
types of kicks in soccer
Okay, so let's take a look at this
The first one is goal kick a goal kick.
Okay goal kick. So who does the goal kick?
It's usually the goalie or the goalkeeper.
All right. Who takes the goal kick?
Okay, so when the goalie kicks the ball
Now what about a corner kick? Okay, so
if the team is attacking and the ball goes
Out of bounds in the
back area near the goal
Then they get a corner kick. They've got to
kick the ball from the corner of the field
This is a great chance
to score a goal, isn't it?
Exactly. Yes. Okay, and
our final kick a penalty kick
penalty kick penalty
kick. So if a player gets
fouled while he is in
the area near the goal
Okay, he gets a penalty kick.
So basically it's just him
I think it's 13 or 15 steps
away from the goalie
And he gets the opportunity
to score or to kick the ball
So there are no defenders or
other players in the way. Nobody
Wow another great
chance to score a goal.
All right. Well, these
are all great soccer words
I think we should hear
them again in context.
So let's listen this
time a little bit slower
Welcome back soccer fans
My name is Rick Fields and
as always I am joined by my
Commentating wingman Bob Copeland and
we're on the brink of soccer history today
As Ecuador and Brazil are tied one one
As we begin the second half of the 2022
World Cup
The ref calls the players for
the kickoff and here we go
Ecuador quickly passes the
ball to the midfield, but oh
It's out of bounds that
will be a throw in for Brazil
At the gianu has the ball
and makes a long pass
to Lubino and the ref
has called him upside
No question about it.
He was offside by a mile
We have a goal kick for Ecuador. Edison
Mendez heads it to Valencia. He shoots
Deflected by the defender
and we have a corner kick
Delgado takes the corner
Now we have a foul. Oh, no
Dada the goalkeeper has
fouled the Ecuadorian player
He gets a yellow card and
that will be a penalty kick
This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to
get ahead in this match
and become world champions
He gets ready for the kick.
He shoots and he
All right, so we heard these words
that we were talking about in context
And now some really
interesting phrases came up
And this would be a good time to
take a look at them in fluency builder
Fluency builder
Well Marco there are three great phrases
in this dialogue that I want to look at
The first one on the brink of
We are on the brink of
We're on the brink
of soccer history.
Okay, so on the brink of what is
it? What exactly does that mean?
Well, why don't we hear some examples
to help us understand the meaning
Example one
Look, we don't have any money.
We're on the brink of going bankrupt
Example two
The two countries are on the brink of war
Example three
We're on the brink of
an important discovery
All right, so great examples
on the brink of a critical point.
Exactly. It means you're
almost there, right?
Okay, yeah, very good
And what about this next phrase
that I saw and it was really interesting.
No question about
it. No question about it
No question about it.
No question about it. All right, so
This is a statement that
doesn't really make much sense
But what am I saying when I say oh no
question about it? You're saying I agree
There is no doubt
you're right. You're right.
Mm-hmm. Okay. Well,
let's give some examples
I could say there's no question
about it Ecuador is a great soccer team
There is no question
about that. All right, so
or you can say no question
about it our company
Makes the best products
on the market. Okay, so really
useful phrase that you can
use in sports or anywhere else
Okay, and Now let's take a look at
our last phrase for fluency builder
And it's a really good one to
exaggerate a little bit. Okay, by a mile
By a mile by a mile.
So he was offside by a mile, right?
So the commentator is
saying that he was very
offside that it was
really obvious, right?
So you can use that
also in different contexts.
Maybe not in sports.
Okay, so maybe we can say
Our company is ahead of
all the others by a mile, right?
Or if you tell somebody to
guess your age and they say oh,
I think you are 42. Oh, you
could say you're off by a mile
So you're really
really wrong Exactly.
Yeah, so it's a way of
exaggerating a little bit.
Yes, something is
really obvious right?
Well three awesome phrases
and I think it will help us to
hear them one more time.
So let's listen to the dialogue
And
Welcome back soccer fans.
My name is Rick Fields and as always
I am joined by my commentating
wingman Bob Copeland
and we are in the break
of soccer history today as
Ecuador and Brazil are tied one one
as we begin the second half of the 2022
World Cup The ref calls the
players for the kickoff and here we go
Ecuador quickly passes the
ball to the midfield but oh,
no, it's out of bounds.
That'll be a throw in for Brazil
I think I knew has the
ball and makes a long pass
to Hoeenio and the ref
is calling them offside
No question about it.
He was offside by a mile
We have an old kick record
or Edison Mendez heads
of tovola chill. He shoots
deflected by the defender
And we have a corner kick then
Gallo takes the corner. We have a foul
Oh no, Dita the goalkeeper
has foul decadorean player.
He gets a yellow card and
that will be a penalty kick
This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to
get ahead in this match
and become world champions
He gets ready for the
kick he shoots and he
Okay, well as you all
may know soccer is a
very popular sport
especially in Latin America
That's right, and your
favorite team Ecuador.
Are they are they really
this good in soccer?
They're really gonna
win the 2022 Cup.
Well, maybe not. Well, actually
Ecuador has has improved with time
But usually it's the strong
teams like Argentina
and Brazil who dominate
the region, right?
Right, but yeah, hopefully
we'll make it next time.
Okay. Well, I have my money
on Ecuador and for 2022
But yeah, not on Canada.
There's no hope for us.
Well Canada is doing
really well now. They actually
Beat Mexico if I'm not mistaken.
Oh, actually that sort of yeah,
I kind of remember that now
But there's I think there's
no hope for us to be
Brazil or Argentina one
of these big countries
We have the next world
cup coming up so it's really
exciting and I don't know
who's gonna win. All right, well
Listeners, who do you think is going to
win? Who is the best soccer team out there?
Right, they're really good soccer
teams although some of our
some countries aren't really
known for their soccer like Russia
You don't really hear too much
soccer from Russia really or from
China is for that. I wonder how
popular it is in these countries
So let us know come to
our website englishpot.
com tell us how popular
soccer is in your country or
What team you are a fan of? I know many
people like the European cups and they are
fans of Barcelona or the Italian
teams. We'll come to the website
Marco and I are always around to answer
your questions and until next time goodbye